<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<?xml-stylesheet href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl" type="text/xsl" media="screen"

?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css" type="text/css" media

="screen"?><!-- generator="wordpress/2.0" --><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content

/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version

="2.0">

<channel>

	<title>jQuery Blog</title>

	<link>http://jquery.com/blog</link>

	<description>New Wave Javascript.</description>

	<pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2007 14:42:46 +0000</pubDate>

	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.0</generator>

	<language>en</language>

			<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com

/jquery" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>

		<title>Google Groups and Amazon S3</title>

		<link>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/04/02/google-groups-and-amazon-s3/</link>

		<comments>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/04/02/google-groups-and-amazon-s3/#comments</comments>

		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2007 05:15:47 +0000</pubDate>

		<dc:creator>John Resig</dc:creator>

		

	<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jquery.com/blog/2007/04/02/google-groups-and-amazon-s3/</guid>

		<description><![CDATA[Two new improvements have just gone into place to help improve the quality of

 the jQuery site.

The jQuery Mailing List is now hosted with Google Groups.

This move is going to help provide huge increases in the overall speed, and quality, of the jQuery mailing

 list. At the time of the move we were sending out, [...]]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two new improvements have just gone into place to help improve the quality

 of the jQuery site.</p>

<p><b>The <a href="http://groups.google.com/group/jquery-en">jQuery Mailing List</a> is now hosted with

 <a href="http://groups.google.com/">Google Groups</a>.</b></p>

<p>This move is going to help provide huge increases in the overall speed, and quality, of the jQuery

 mailing list. At the time of the move we were sending out, approximately, 4.5m emails per month. Unfortunately

, the list was prone to folding under the high server load; and the amount of effort required to keep

 it performing nicely was simply too much to ignore.</p>

<p>The best feature of the <a href="http://groups.google.com/group/jquery-en">new mailing list</a> (besides

 the increased reliability) is the addition of Google Groups&#8217; wonderful web-based interface. I

 hope that everyone who&#8217;s asked for a forum can now be content knowing that they can browse the

 jQuery list, and easily reply to posts, without ever having to subscribe to incoming messages.</p>

<p><b>Note:</b> If you were a member of the old mailing list, you should be completely moved to the new

 one. All old messages and users were moved over, and everything should be intact.</p>

<p>Complete instructions on how to use the main discussion mailing list, and all the other jQuery mailing

 lists, can be found on here: <a href="http://docs.jquery.com/Discussion">jQuery Mailing Lists</a>.<

/p>

<p><b>All code is now hosted with <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/s3">Amazon S3</a>.</b></p>

<p>As a project, we&#8217;ve never discouraged first time users from using the <a href="http://docs.jquery

.com/Downloading_jQuery">jQuery Source Code</a> straight from their personal site; it helps to get new

 users started with development, without having to worry about keeping their code up to date.</p>

<p>Needless to say, the number of users who&#8217;ve directly used the jQuery source directly from the

 jQuery site has increased dramatically in recent months (with some large-scale sites directly pulling

 from jQuery.com). This still isn&#8217;t a huge problem, but it&#8217;s something that the web server

 hosting jQuery.com shouldn&#8217;t have to worry about. For that reason, all jQuery source code has

 been moved to Amazon S3, for example: <a href="http://code.jquery.com/jquery-latest.js">http://code

.jquery.com/jquery-latest.js</a>.</p>

<p>The jQuery site has been using the code directly from Amazon S3 for over two weeks now and I&#8217

;ve been very pleased with the results. The number of files requested has dropped dramatically, giving

 the web server more time to serve the normal jQuery web pages.</p>

<p><b>Note:</b> All old requests to http://jquery.com/src/&#8230; are being redirected to the http:/

/code.jquery.com/&#8230; sub-domain (which is managed by Amazon).</p>

<p>A nice thing about this move is that we can soon start providing dedicated hosting for plugins. Once

 we figure out the logistics of the plugin repository (which is currently under development), we&#8217

;ll be sure to make that a priority.</p>

<p>Additionally, static jQuery.com files (like stylesheets, images, and JavaScript files) are being hosted

 directly from Amazon S3 too (static.jquery.com). This is also helping to alleviate any strain on the

 server that may be present.</p>

<p>As always, if you get any errors on the jQuery site, please be sure to send a message to the <a href

="http://groups.google.com/group/jquery-en">mailing list</a>, where we can find it and help to solve

 the problem.</p>

<p><b>1.1.3 News</b></p>

<p>All of these site issues have delayed jQuery 1.1.3 slightly, but now that they&#8217;re out of the

 way we should be back on track for having a 1.1.3 alpha out by the end of this week. This update is

 going to include significant updates to the performance of jQuery animations and huge speed increases

 to the selector engine; as well as fixing over 20 outstanding bugs. We hope to have an update concerning

 all of this, shortly.

</p>

]]></content:encoded>

			<wfw:commentRSS>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/04/02/google-groups-and-amazon-s3/feed/</wfw:commentRSS

>

		</item>

		<item>

		<title>jQuery Book Coming Soon</title>

		<link>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/03/26/jquery-book-coming-soon/</link>

		<comments>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/03/26/jquery-book-coming-soon/#comments</comments>

		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2007 11:42:14 +0000</pubDate>

		<dc:creator>Karl Swedberg</dc:creator>

		

	<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jquery.com/blog/2007/03/26/jquery-book-coming-soon/</guid>

		<description><![CDATA[For those of you who have been following the jQuery blog the past couple months

, you may have noticed John Resig&#8217;s mention of a secret: &#8220;There&#8217;s a jQuery book in

 the works!&#8221; Well, I am thrilled to be able to leak a little more information about that secret

.

For the past few months my friend Jonathan [...]]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For those of you who have been following the jQuery blog the past couple

 months, you may have noticed <a href="http://jquery.com/blog/2007/01/14/jquery-birthday-11-new-site-new-docs

/">John Resig&#8217;s mention of a secret</a>: &#8220;There&#8217;s a jQuery book in the works!&#8221

; Well, I am thrilled to be able to leak a little more information about that secret.</p>

<p>For the past few months my friend Jonathan Chaffer and I have been hard at work on the book, and everything

 is progressing well. Our writing is being supported by a stellar group of technical reviewers, some

 of whom are members of the jQuery development team. We&#8217;ll be able to divulge details about the

 book&#8217;s contents soon. The publisher is readying a web page for it, so as soon as that is completed

, we can give you the full scoop.</p>

<h2>About the Authors</h2>

<p>Jonathan Chaffer is a long-time Drupal contributor and creator of Drupal&#8217;s CCK. He also likes

 to make up bizarre band names and album titles, based on snippets of conversations he overhears, at

 <a href="http://www.tweaktheviking.com/">Tweak the Viking</a>. Karl Swedberg (that&#8217;s me) is a

 <a href="http://jquery.com/blog/2006/12/18/meet-the-people-behind-jquery/">jQuery zealot</a> who runs

 the <a href="http://www.learningjquery.com/">Learning jQuery</a> blog and still tries to keep a bit

 of his former career as an English teacher alive at his other blog, <a href="http://www.englishrules

.com/">English Rules</a>. Jonathan and Karl work together at <a href="http://www.structureinteractive

.com/">Structure Interactive</a> in Grand Rapids, Michigan, where they have been given a lot of freedom

 to use jQuery, as well as standards-based, semantic HTML &amp; CSS, in many of their projects.

</p>

]]></content:encoded>

			<wfw:commentRSS>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/03/26/jquery-book-coming-soon/feed/</wfw:commentRSS>

		</item>

		<item>

		<title>SXSWi jQuery Meetup</title>

		<link>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/03/11/sxswi-jquery-meetup/</link>

		<comments>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/03/11/sxswi-jquery-meetup/#comments</comments>

		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2007 06:49:09 +0000</pubDate>

		<dc:creator>John Resig</dc:creator>

		

	<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jquery.com/blog/2007/03/11/sxswi-jquery-meetup/</guid>

		<description><![CDATA[Right now the annual SXSWi conference is happening in beautiful, sunny, Austin

, Texas. Interestingly enough, there&#8217;s a ton of jQuery users here (as am I). I&#8217;ve already

 had the opportunity to talk with a number of you, but we should really do a proper get together.

As proposed by Luke Lutman, on the mailing list, and [...]]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Right now the annual SXSWi conference is happening in beautiful, sunny

, Austin, Texas. Interestingly enough, there&#8217;s a ton of jQuery users here (as am I). I&#8217;ve

 already had the opportunity to talk with a number of you, but we should really do a proper get together

.</p>

<p>As proposed by Luke Lutman, on the mailing list, and Cody Lindley (of Thickbox fame) - let&#8217;s

 do a meetup! Let&#8217;s say Monday (Mar 12th) at lunch. Meet at the main doors facing the Courtyard

 Hotel. If you have any troubles, feel free to give me a call at 585-615-5287 and I&#8217;ll direct you

 in.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m looking forward to meeting everyone!</p>

<p><b>See Also:</b> <a href="http://upcoming.org/event/162778/">http://upcoming.org/event/162778/</a

></p>

<p><b>Update:</b> Just to clarify, this is at 12:30pm (after the 11:30am-12:30pm session ends). And the

 doors are at the corner of Trinity and and Fourth St. I&#8217;ll be wearing a bright red Atari T-Shirt

, so I should be easy to spot.

</p>

]]></content:encoded>

			<wfw:commentRSS>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/03/11/sxswi-jquery-meetup/feed/</wfw:commentRSS>

		</item>

		<item>

		<title>jQuery 1.1.2</title>

		<link>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/27/jquery-112/</link>

		<comments>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/27/jquery-112/#comments</comments>

		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2007 04:28:34 +0000</pubDate>

		<dc:creator>John Resig</dc:creator>

		

	<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/27/jquery-112/</guid>

		<description><![CDATA[Translations: Italiano, français

The release of jQuery 1.1.2 is upon us! This is a another bug fix release. We&#8217;ve fixed a number

 of outstanding issues. The fixes have been tested well, so there shouldn&#8217;t be any regressions

 (knock on wood). The most noticeable issue that was resolved was related to animation flickers when

 doing a slideDown.

It [...]]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>Translations:</b> <a href="http://www.jquery.info/spip.php?article43"

>Italiano</a>, <a href="http://www.jquery.info/spip.php?article42">français</a></p>

<p>The release of jQuery 1.1.2 is upon us! This is a another bug fix release. We&#8217;ve fixed a number

 of outstanding issues. The fixes have been tested well, so there shouldn&#8217;t be any regressions

 (knock on wood). The most noticeable issue that was resolved was related to animation flickers when

 doing a slideDown.</p>

<p><b>It is highly recommended that you upgrade.</b></p>

<p>As always, if you have any questions or concerns with new release, please feel free to discuss it

 on the <a href="http://docs.jquery.com/Discussion#Mailing_Lists">jQuery Mailing List</a>. If you think

 you&#8217;ve spotted a bug, please <a href="http://dev.jquery.com/newticket">add it to the bug tracker

</a>.</p>

<h2>Download</h2>

<ul>

<li><b><a href="http://jquery.com/src/jquery-1.1.2.pack.js">Compressed JavaScript</a></b> (Recommended

 Download!)</li>

<li><a href="http://jquery.com/src/jquery-1.1.2.js">Uncompressed JavaScript</a></li>

<li><a href="http://jquery.com/src/jquery-1.1.2.release.zip">Full Release (jQuery, Test Suite, Documentation

)</a></li>

<li><a href="http://jquery.com/src/jquery-1.1.2.build.zip">Build Files (Compile your own version of jQuery

 1.1.2)</a></li>

</ul>

<h2>Bug Fixes</h2>

<p>The most important bug fixes, relevant to this release, are as follows:</p>

<ol>

<li>Change: Event handlers (like <code>element.onclick</code>) are now removed when no more functions

 are bound to the event.</li>

<li>Fixed: DOM Manipulations for form elements.</li>

<li>Fixed: <code>jQuery.isFunction</code> to return false on nodes.</li>

<li>Fixed: <code>jQuery.className.has</code>, escaping regex characters in <code>className</code> (for

 metadata)</li>

<li>Fixed: an issue in IE where an event on a cloned element is fired during a <code>.clone()</code>

 inside of an event handler.</li>

<li>Fixed: IE ID selectors selecting by the name attribute.</li>

<li>Changed: Events are now internally stored in <code>elem.$events</code> rather than <code>elem.events

</code> (due to a nasty bug relating to DOM 0 expandos).</li>

<li>Changed: <code>.attr('href')</code> is now consistent in all browsers.</li>

<li>Changed: <code>@href</code> is now consistent in all browsers.</li>

<li>Fixed: the <code>slideDown</code> flickering bug.</li>

<li>Fixed: Having a <code>\r</code> endline in <code>$("...")</code> caused a never-ending loop.</li

>

<li>Fixed: IE6 AJAX memory leak</li>

<li>Fixed: bug in pushStack, reporting an element at <code>[0]</code> in a jQuery object with length

 0</li>

</ol>

<h2>Documentation</h2>

<p>Additionally, the documentation has been back-ported out of the wiki and into the API docs. All of

 the documentation resources have been updated in respect to the 1.1.2 release.</p>

<ul>

<li>Official Documentation:<br />

<a href="http://docs.jquery.com/">http://docs.jquery.com/</a></li>

<li>API Browsers:<br />

<a href="http://jquery.bassistance.de/api-browser/">http://jquery.bassistance.de/api-browser/</a><br

 />

<a href="http://jquery.com/api/">http://jquery.com/api/</a></li>

</ul>

<h3>Leading up to jQuery 1.1.3&#8230;</h3>

<p>This may seem like a fairly light bug fix release, but we&#8217;re gearing up to the release of jQuery

 1.1.3. A number of outstanding bugs (about 5-10) require significant changes to how jQuery works, internally

 (specifically, in relation to events and animations). We want to make <b>100% certain</b> that there

 are no regressions made to these important pieces of code.</p>

<p>We have patches nearly ready (animation is ready, events is in the works) - and when that&#8217;s

 the case, we&#8217;re going to release a preview of the 1.1.3 code so that everyone can test against

 it.</p>

<p><b>Update:</b> This has also been announced on <a href="http://www.learningjquery.com/">Learning jQuery

</a>: <a href="http://www.learningjquery.com/2007/02/jquery-112-released">jQuery 1.1.2 Released</a><

/p>

<p><big><b>Update:</b></big> A nasty glitch in Safari was found and fixed. We just re-tagged jQuery 

(it&#8217;s now SVN rev 1465 instead of 1460 - this includes a fix for the bug, and it temporarily disables

 the test suite in Safari) and all the jQuery 1.1.2 downloads should be updated, as well.

</p>

]]></content:encoded>

			<wfw:commentRSS>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/27/jquery-112/feed/</wfw:commentRSS>

		</item>

		<item>

		<title>jQuery is OpenAjax Compliant</title>

		<link>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/21/jquery-is-openajax-compliant/</link>

		<comments>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/21/jquery-is-openajax-compliant/#comments</comments>

		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2007 05:53:33 +0000</pubDate>

		<dc:creator>John Resig</dc:creator>

		

	<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/21/jquery-is-openajax-compliant/</guid>

		<description><![CDATA[

A new initiative has been forming, over the recent months, in an attempt to standardize the different

 Ajax and JavaScript codebases that exist. A number of corporate entities have come together to draft

 the new OpenAjax standard (including IBM, Adobe, Opera, and Mozilla).

Today we&#8217;re announcing a new plugin that you can use to make jQuery [...]]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img id="image139" src="http://jquery.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007

/02/openajax.png" alt="OpenAjax Alliance" style="float:right;" /></p>

<p>A <a href="http://www.openajax.org/">new initiative</a> has been forming, over the recent months,

 in an attempt to standardize the different Ajax and JavaScript codebases that exist. A number of corporate

 entities have come together to draft the new <a href="http://www.openajax.org/">OpenAjax</a> standard

 (including IBM, Adobe, Opera, and Mozilla).</p>

<p>Today we&#8217;re announcing a <a href="http://dev.jquery.com/browser/trunk/plugins/openajax/lib/jQuery

/OpenAjax.js">new plugin</a> that you can use to make jQuery OpenAjax compliant. By doing this, jQuery

 is becoming one of the first projects that has made its codebase compliant with the new standard.</p

>

<p>Currently, the <a href="http://www.openajax.org/member/wiki/InteropFest_2007_March">requirements for

 compliance</a> are, relatively, simple - but still quite important. The relevant rules can be summarized

 as such:</p>

<ul>

<li>All libraries must register themselves (their name, version, and namespace) with the main OpenAjax

 library.</li>

<li>All libraries must register any global variables that they use  (in the case of jQuery it&#8217;s

 &#8216;jQuery&#8217;, and optionally &#8216;$&#8217; - it defaults to just including &#8216;jQuery&

#8217;).</li>

<li>Any attempt to register &#8220;onload&#8221; or &#8220;onunload&#8221; handlers must go through the

 OpenAjax library. In the case of jQuery, if you do: $(window).load(function), and OpenAjax is included

, jQuery will defer to OpenAjax&#8217;s solution.</li>

<li>Libraries must not disrupt the ability of other libraries to traverse the HTML DOM document.</li

>

</ul>

<p>You can view <a href="http://john.jquery.com/plugins/openajax/tests/">jQuery&#8217;s compliance results

</a>, to verify that it does, indeed, past the test suite.</p>

<p>If you wish to use jQuery in conjunction with other OpenAjax-capable libraries, the process is rather

 straight forward.</p>

<p><b>Step 1</b> Download a copy of the <a href="http://dev.jquery.com/browser/trunk/plugins/openajax

/lib/jQuery/OpenAjax.js?format=txt">jQuery OpenAjax plugin</a> to your server.</p>

<p><b>Step 2</b> Include the library in your site, just after you include jQuery.

<pre>&lt;script src="<a href="http://jquery.com/src/jquery-latest.js">jquery.js</a>&#8220;>&lt;/script

>

&lt;script src=&#8221;<a href="http://dev.jquery.com/browser/trunk/plugins/openajax/lib/jQuery/OpenAjax

.js?format=txt">jquery.openajax.js</a>&#8220;>&lt;/script></pre>

<p>Be sure to include both jQuery and the jQuery OpenAjax plugin after you&#8217;ve included the official

 OpenAjax library itself.</p>

<p>And that&#8217;s it! jQuery will now happily play with the OpenAjax core library.</p>

<p>It should be noted that, currently, jQuery is not part of the <a href="http://www.openajax.org/">OpenAjax

 Alliance</a>, but we&#8217;re in the process of applying and are eager to begin actively participating

.

</p>

]]></content:encoded>

			<wfw:commentRSS>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/21/jquery-is-openajax-compliant/feed/</wfw:commentRSS

>

		</item>

		<item>

		<title>jQuery and Jack Slocum’s Ext</title>

		<link>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/19/jquery-and-jack-slocums-ext/</link>

		<comments>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/19/jquery-and-jack-slocums-ext/#comments</comments>

		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2007 00:17:27 +0000</pubDate>

		<dc:creator>John Resig</dc:creator>

		

	<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/19/jquery-and-jack-slocums-ext/</guid>

		<description><![CDATA[

Today, we’re proud to announce that the jQuery Project and Jack Slocum’s Ext Project, have partnered

 to integrate the amazingly lightweight and powerful jQuery framework with Ext’s awesome UI library.

 This collaboration will greatly enhance the capabilities of both projects and expand the functionality

 available to developers using the jQuery JavaScript Library and the Ext [...]]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img id="image132" src="http://jquery.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007

/02/extjs.png" alt="Ext JavaScript Library" height="92" width="128" style="float: right;"/></p>

<p><iframe src='http://digg.com/api/diggthis.php?u=http://digg.com/programming/jQuery_Ext_Partner_to_Deliver_Integrated_JavaScript_UI_Features'

 height='82' width='55' frameborder='0' scrolling='no' style="float: right;"></iframe></p>

<p>Today, we’re proud to announce that the <a href="http://jquery.com/">jQuery Project</a> and <a href

="http://jackslocum.com/">Jack Slocum</a>’s <a href="http://yui-ext.com/">Ext Project</a>, have partnered

 to integrate the amazingly lightweight and powerful jQuery framework with Ext’s awesome UI library.

 This collaboration will greatly enhance the capabilities of both projects and expand the functionality

 available to developers using the jQuery JavaScript Library and the Ext UI component suite.</p>

<p>Specifically, the upcoming Ext 1.0 release will be able to run, natively, on the jQuery JavaScript

 Library. No other libraries will be required. The jQuery and Ext teams are actively working together

 to bring this integration to the Ext codebase.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s some possible questions and answers (feel free to post any others that you have in the

 comments):</p>

<p><strong>What prompted the collaboration?</strong></p>

<p>Ext has some fantastic components - arguably, the best on the web. jQuery has all the core functionality

 to support what Ext has. The jQuery team contacted Jack Slocum with the hopes that we could work together

 to add jQuery support to the Ext library, and Jack whole-heartedly agreed. It&#8217;s a win-win situation

: jQuery gets some awesome components, Ext gets a huge influx of new users.</p>

<p><strong>What are the benefits for jQuery and Ext users?</strong></p>

<p>jQuery users gain a huge number of expertly-designed components that they will be able to deploy immediately

. Additionally, they&#8217;ll be able to use them in a manner that better suits the jQuery philosophy

 (e.g. being able to call Ext queries on sets of elements, chaining calls, leveraging jQuery&#8217;s

 support for true unobtrusive DOM scripting etc.)</p>

<p>At the same time, existing Ext users will gain the flexibility of being able to continue to use Ext

’s professional-caliber components while leveraging the lightweight, small (~19k) and powerful jQuery

 framework.</p>

<p><strong>How will the two teams work together?</strong></p>

<p>After the first beta release of Ext 1.0, jQuery will be providing a<br />

strike team which will work to iron out all the integration points in Ext. At the same time, Jack will

 be working to isolate all the remaining framework-specific code, making it easier for us to finish the

 conversion process. All of this will be in place for Ext&#8217;s final 1.0 release, which will support

 both Yahoo UI and jQuery.</p>

<p><strong>How will support be handled?</strong></p>

<p>The jQuery team will be providing support for any bugs that may only exist in the jQuery version of

 Ext.</p>

<p>Support for Ext, itself, will continue to be handled via the <a href="http://www.yui-ext.com/forum

/">Ext forums</a>. The Ext project will also begin offering a level of paid support for its corporate

 users.</p>

<p><strong>What Ext features will be included in Ext 1.0 for jQuery</strong></p>

<p>All available Ext 1.0 features are going to be supported by jQuery.</p>

<p>The final feature list, for Ext 1.0, is still being finalized but a full breadth of new functionality

 can be expected.</p>

<p><strong>When will Ext 1.0 for jQuery be available?</strong></p>

<p>The final release date still has yet to be finalized and we will make a formal announcement on the

 jQuery blog, the jQuery mailing list, the Ext project site, and the Ext forums once the its ready to

 go.</p>

<p>An <a href="http://www.yui-ext.com/forum/viewtopic.php?t=2819">alpha release of Ext 1.0</a> was just

 released, but does not, yet, include the jQuery compatibility layer.</p>

<p><strong>Do any licensing issues exist?</strong></p>

<p>No. jQuery’s licensing will remain the same, and Ext 1.0 will be completely open source (LGPL).</p

>

<p>Additionally, corporations <a href="http://www.yui-ext.com/forum/viewtopic.php?t=2737">will be able

 to purchase</a> an Ext support license. This will include email support and SVN access, amongst other

 features.</p>

<p><b>Update:</b> <a href="http://digg.com/programming/jQuery_Ext_Partner_to_Deliver_Integrated_JavaScript_UI_Features"

>Digg this story up!</a></p>

<h2>Examples</h2>

<p>Here are examples of what you can do with Ext. (All demos currently run on Yahoo UI, as the Ext 1

.0 alpha release doesn&#8217;t support jQuery.)</p>

<p><b>Paged, Dynamic, Grids</b></p>

<p><a href="http://yui-ext.com/deploy/ext-1.0-alpha1/examples/grid/paging.html"><img id="image137" src

="http://jquery.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/02/Picture%206.png" alt="Ext Paged Grid" style="border

:0"/></a></p>

<p><b>Mixed Content Menus</b></p>

<p><a href="http://yui-ext.com/deploy/ext-1.0-alpha1/examples/menu/menus.html"><img id="image136" src

="http://jquery.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/02/Picture%207.png" alt="Ext Mixed Content Menus" style

="border:0"/></a></p>

<p><b>Advanced Dialog Layout and Themes</b></p>

<p><a href="http://yui-ext.com/deploy/ext-1.0-alpha1/examples/dialog/layout.html"><img id="image133"

 src="http://jquery.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/02/Picture%203.png" alt="Ext Dialog Layout" style

="border:0"/></a></p>

<p><b>Message Box Dialog</b></p>

<p><a href="http://yui-ext.com/deploy/ext-1.0-alpha1/examples/dialog/msg-box.html"><img id="image134"

 src="http://jquery.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/02/Picture%204.png" alt="Ext Message Box Dialog"

 style="border:0"/></a></p>

<p><b>Drag-and-Drop Trees</b></p>

<p><a href="http://yui-ext.com/deploy/ext-1.0-alpha1/examples/tree/two-trees.html"><img id="image135"

 src="http://jquery.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/02/Picture%205.png" alt="Ext Drag and Drop Trees"

 style="border:0"/></a>

</p>

]]></content:encoded>

			<wfw:commentRSS>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/19/jquery-and-jack-slocums-ext/feed/</wfw:commentRSS

>

		</item>

		<item>

		<title>The jQuery IRC Channel</title>

		<link>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/17/the-jquery-irc-channel/</link>

		<comments>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/17/the-jquery-irc-channel/#comments</comments>

		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2007 00:38:41 +0000</pubDate>

		<dc:creator>wycats</dc:creator>

		

	<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/17/the-jquery-irc-channel/</guid>

		<description><![CDATA[In addition to jQuery&#8217;s great Mailing List and Documentation, there&#8217

;s another place where users can seek  help about jQuery problems: We have a very active jQuery IRC channel

.

Even though it&#8217;s never really been publicly announced, the channel currently averages over 50 simultaneous

 users, including some friendly jQuery bots! Hosted on irc.freenode.net, #jquery always has [...]]]>

</description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In addition to jQuery&#8217;s great <a href="http://jquery.com/discuss

/">Mailing List</a> and <a href="http://docs.jquery.com/Main_Page">Documentation</a>, there&#8217;s another

 place where users can seek  help about jQuery problems: <b>We have a very active jQuery IRC channel

.</b></p>

<p>Even though it&#8217;s never really been publicly announced, the channel currently averages over 50

 simultaneous users, including some friendly jQuery bots! Hosted on irc.freenode.net, #jquery always

 has users who are online and willing to answer your questions (of which, they are often answered within

 minutes of their being asked).</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s the information that you will need in order to <a href="irc://irc.freenode.net/jquery"

>connect to the channel</a>:<br />

<b>Server:</b> irc.freenode.net<br />

<b>Room:</b> #jquery</p>

<p><a href="http://docs.jquery.com/Contributors">jQuery team members</a>, especially <a href="http:/

/ejohn.org/">John Resig</a> (nick: JohnResig), <a href="http://bassistance.de/">Joern Zaefferer</a> 

(nick: JoernZaefferer), and <a href="http://yehudakatz.com/">Yehuda Katz</a> (nick: wycats) are frequently

 in attendance, helping experienced and new users alike with both complex and trivial problems.</p>

<p>The IRC Channel is best if you need quick help with any of the following:

<ul>

<li>JavaScript</li>

<li>jQuery Syntax</li>

<li>Problem Solving</li>

<li>Strange bugs</li>

</ul>

<p><br/></p>

<p>If your problem is more in-depth, we may ask you to post to the <a href="http://jquery.com/discuss

/">mailing list</a>, or the <a href="http://jquery.com/dev/bugs/">bug tracker</a>, so that we can help

 you in a more-suitable environment.</p>

<p>Additionally, we recently started logging the channel, so you can now look back through to find answers

 to your old problems: <a href="http://jquery.com/discuss/irc/">jQuery IRC channel Log</a>

</p>

]]></content:encoded>

			<wfw:commentRSS>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/17/the-jquery-irc-channel/feed/</wfw:commentRSS>

		</item>

		<item>

		<title>jQuery Nightly Builds</title>

		<link>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/13/jquery-nightly-builds/</link>

		<comments>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/13/jquery-nightly-builds/#comments</comments>

		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2007 03:40:09 +0000</pubDate>

		<dc:creator>Paul McLanahan</dc:creator>

		

	<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/13/jquery-nightly-builds/</guid>

		<description><![CDATA[After much wailing and gnashing of teeth by certain members of the discussion

 mailing list (read: me), we now have automated nightly builds of jQuery ready for mass consumption.

 These builds came about at the request of we community members who would like to experiment with the

 most recent features of jQuery on our projects, [...]]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After much wailing and gnashing of teeth by certain members of the <a

 href="http://jquery.com/discuss/">discussion mailing list</a> (read: me), we now have automated nightly

 builds of jQuery ready for mass consumption. These builds came about at the request of we community

 members who would like to experiment with the most recent features of jQuery on our projects, but who

, for whatever reason, find ourselves behind firewalls that restrict our access to the <a href="http

://docs.jquery.com/Downloading_jQuery">subversion repository</a>.</p>

<p>Without further ado, here are the gory details: You can get your bleeding-edge-jQuery fix at <a href

="http://jquery.com/src/nightlies/">http://jquery.com/src/nightlies/</a>. This folder will simply show

 you a list of available files. There are 4 files in there in which most of you will be most interested

&#8230;</p>

<ol>

<li><a href="http://jquery.com/src/nightlies/jquery-nightly.js">jquery-nightly.js</a> - Pretty self-explainatory

. It&#8217;s the uncompressed jQuery. Mmmm&#8230; fresh from the repository</li>

<li><a href="http://jquery.com/src/nightlies/jquery-nightly.pack.js">jquery-nightly.pack.js</a> - As

 the more perceptive of you have already guessed, it&#8217;s the <a href="http://dean.edwards.name/packer

/">packed</a> version of #1</li>

<li><a href="http://jquery.com/src/nightlies/jquery-nightly.release.zip">jquery-nightly.release.zip<

/a> - This contains the docs, test suite, and all of the pre-built versions of jQuery</li>

<li><a href="http://jquery.com/src/nightlies/jquery-nightly.build.zip">jquery-nightly.build.zip</a> -

 Is the real win for we poor souls behind the fiery-walls of the corporate world. It contains the full

 jquery path from the repo, and is everything you need to build your very own jQuery</li>

</ol>

<p>The nightlies folder will also fill up with dated versions of all 4 of these files so that you can

 go find jQuery at whatever vintage you prefer.</p>

<p>New versions of the nightlies will be added every day at 2am EST (7am GMT), and will consist of the

 most recent revision from the subversion repository at that time.</p>

<p>If all of this talk of subversion, repositories, bleeding-edge, and nightly building makes the stability

 craving web deveoper inside you run away screaming, fear not. The <a href="http://jquery.com/">stable

 release download</a> you need is still right here waiting for you. </p>

<p>Thanks go to <a href="http://ejohn.org/">John Resig</a> for hooking us up with the server-side magic

 that got this automated build process running (not to mention for the server, the bandwidth, and for

 jQuery in general <img src='http://jquery.com/blog/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt='

:)' class='wp-smiley' />  ).

</p>

]]></content:encoded>

			<wfw:commentRSS>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/13/jquery-nightly-builds/feed/</wfw:commentRSS>

		</item>

		<item>

		<title>New jQuery Project Team Members</title>

		<link>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/02/new-jquery-project-team-members/</link>

		<comments>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/02/new-jquery-project-team-members/#comments</comments>

		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2007 21:27:43 +0000</pubDate>

		<dc:creator>ReyBango</dc:creator>

		

	<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/02/new-jquery-project-team-members/</guid

>

		<description><![CDATA[The jQuery team would like to welcome our newest team members, Yehuda  Katz,

 Nate Cavanaugh, &#038; Klaus Hartl. These three developers have made invaluable contributions to the

 jQuery projects in terms of time, knowledge and commitment to the community.

Yehuda is a developer living in New York City who maintains the web site  Visual [...]]]></description

>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://docs.jquery.com/About/Contributors">jQuery team<

/a> would like to welcome our newest team members, <strong><a href="http://yehudakatz.com/">Yehuda  Katz

</a></strong>, <strong><a href="http://alterform.com/">Nate Cavanaugh</a></strong>, &#038; <strong><a

 href="http://stilbuero.de/">Klaus Hartl</a></strong>. These three developers have made invaluable contributions

 to the jQuery projects in terms of time, knowledge and commitment to the community.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://yehudakatz.com/">Yehuda</a></strong> is a developer living in New York City

 who maintains the web site  Visual jQuery, and publishes the Visual jQuery Magazine. Additionally, 

 he&#8217;s a frequent contributor to the jQuery Blog and promoter of good  practices within the jQuery

 core. As a member of the evangelism team  he&#8217;s working to help people discover jQuery; actively

 trying to find and  promote jQuery to new users.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://alterform.com/">Nate</a></strong> is a designer living in California. He was

 responsible for the  recent redesign of the jQuery site. He&#8217;s going to be helping to design  new

 portions of the site, and help to bring outdated portions of the site inline with the rest. He&#8217

;s also working to take a critical look at how using jQuery, as a design tool, can help to promote Unobtrusive

 design principals.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://stilbuero.de/">Klaus</a></strong> has been one of the most vocal supporter

 of jQuery and unobtrusive  design on the jQuery mailing list. His ability to expertly explain  quality

, unobtrusive, solutions to problems is invaluable will be a  tremendous boon to the jQuery project.

 Klaus will be working with both  the Evangelism &#038; Dev teams, to help promote jQuery and expand

 its reach  as well as maintaining Thickbox and the Tabs plugin. He will also be  spearheading the effort

 to make Tabs an official plugin.</p>

<p>We&#8217;re very pleased to be working with all of you and welcome you to the <a href="http://docs

.jquery.com/About/Contributors">jQuery team</a>.

</p>

]]></content:encoded>

			<wfw:commentRSS>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/02/02/new-jquery-project-team-members/feed/</wfw:commentRSS

>

		</item>

		<item>

		<title>New jQuery API Browser</title>

		<link>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/01/29/new-jquery-api-browser/</link>

		<comments>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/01/29/new-jquery-api-browser/#comments</comments>

		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2007 15:44:19 +0000</pubDate>

		<dc:creator>ReyBango</dc:creator>

		

	<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jquery.com/blog/2007/01/29/new-jquery-api-browser/</guid>

		<description><![CDATA[

The jQuery team continues to pump out additional tools and resources to make development using jQuery

 easy, efficient and productive. The latest addition to jQuery&#8217;s growing list of tools is project

 team lead Jorn Zaefferer&#8217;s new jQuery API Browser.

Visit: http://jquery.bassistance.de/api-browser/

The jQuery API browser provides an intuitive interface to quickly find information on jQuery&#8217;s

 methods and [...]]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src='http://digg.com/api/diggthis.php?u=http://digg.com/programming

/New_jQuery_JS_Ajax_Library_API_Browser' height='82' width='55' frameborder='0' scrolling='no' style

="float: right;"></iframe></p>

<p>The jQuery team continues to pump out additional tools and resources to make development using jQuery

 easy, efficient and productive. The latest addition to jQuery&#8217;s growing list of tools is project

 team lead Jorn Zaefferer&#8217;s new jQuery API Browser.</p>

<p><center><a target="_blank" href="http://jquery.bassistance.de/api-browser/"><img id="image126" src

="http://jquery.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/01/Screenshot_2.png" alt="jQuery API Browser" height

="249" width="384" /></a><br />

<b>Visit: <a target="_blank" href="http://jquery.bassistance.de/api-browser/">http://jquery.bassistance

.de/api-browser/</a></b></center></p>

<p>The jQuery API browser provides an intuitive interface to quickly find information on jQuery&#8217

;s methods and properties. Features include:</p>

<ul>

<li>Tabbed navigation</li>

<li>Treeview on categories</li>

<li>Quicksearch on both navigation and main content</li>

<li>Code highlighting for both HTML and JavaScript snippets</li>

<li>A vertical splitter that allows you to resize navigation/content panes</li>

<li>Highlighting selected methods in the content</li>

<li>Styled tooltips for method arguments</li>

</ul>

<p>The API browser is available both online and as a download for local usage.</p>

<p>The jQuery project offers a comprehensive &#038; ever-growing list of resources that will provide

 developers with documentation, tutorials, and plugins/widgets for their site development.</p>

<p>jQuery:<br />

<a target="_blank" href="http://jquery.com/">http://jquery.com/</a></p>

<p>Plugins &#038; UI Widgets/Controls:<br />

<a target="_blank" href="http://docs.jquery.com/Plugins">http://docs.jquery.com/Plugins</a></p>

<p>Documentation:<br />

<a target="_blank" href="http://docs.jquery.com/Main_Page">http://docs.jquery.com/Main_Page</a><br /

>

<a target="_blank" href="http://www.visualjquery.com/">http://www.visualjquery.com/</a><br />

<a target="_blank" href="http://jquery.bassistance.de/api-browser/">http://jquery.bassistance.de/api-browser

/</a></p>

<p>Magazine:<br />

<a target="_blank" href="http://www.visualjquery.com/magazine/">http://www.visualjquery.com/magazine

/</a></p>

<p>Mailing List:<br />

<a target="_blank" href="http://jquery.com/discuss/">http://jquery.com/discuss/</a></p>

<p>Project Blog:<br />

<a target="_blank" href="http://jquery.com/blog//">http://jquery.com/blog/</a></p>

<p>Learning Resources:<br />

<a target="_blank" href="http://docs.jquery.com/Tutorials">http://docs.jquery.com/Tutorials</a><br /

>

<a target="_blank" href="http://www.learningjquery.com/">http://www.learningjquery.com/</a><br />

<a target="_blank" href="http://15daysofjquery.com/">http://15daysofjquery.com/</a></p>

<p>About<br />

<a target="_blank" href="http://docs.jquery.com/Sites_Using_jQuery">http://docs.jquery.com/Sites_Using_jQuery

</a><br />

<a target="_blank" href="http://docs.jquery.com/About/Contributors">http://docs.jquery.com/About/Contributors

</a></p>

<p>Don&#8217;t forget to <a href="http://digg.com/programming/New_jQuery_JS_Ajax_Library_API_Browser"

>Digg up this article</a> on Digg!

</p>

]]></content:encoded>

			<wfw:commentRSS>http://jquery.com/blog/2007/01/29/new-jquery-api-browser/feed/</wfw:commentRSS>

		</item>

	<feedburner:awareness xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">http://api.feedburner

.com/awareness/1.0/GetFeedData?uri=jquery</feedburner:awareness></channel>

</rss>